（壁(へき)）皆 ボロボロだな
Everyone's really beat up...
But to be up against Zuoci and such numbers...
しかし あの大人数と左慈(さじ)を相手に
犠牲が２人とは―
and getting through with two sacrifices, the Mountain People are incredible.
山の民 恐るべしというところか
（信(しん)）まあ 大将さえ倒しちまえば
こんなもんよ
Well, if you beat an enemy general, this is what happens.
（貂(てん)）それより 壁
寝てないで大丈夫なの？
Anyhow, Bi, are you gonna be all right with not resting?
（信）
ここまで来て 寝てられっかよ！
He can't sleep after we've come this far!
Right, Brother Bi?!
なあ？ 壁のあんちゃん
（壁）そのとおりだ…
Exactly...
この回廊を抜ければ
直ちに 本殿に着く
When we get down this corridor...
we'll be right at the inner palace.
And in there is the ringleader behind this all,
本殿には
この一件の首謀者 成蟜(せいきょう)がいる
Chengjiao.
（漂(ひょう)）いいな？ 信　託したぞ！
Do you hear me, Xin?!
I'm entrusting this to you!
Are you ready, Xin?
（壁）覚悟はできてるか？ 信
（信）おうよ！
Hell yeah!
成蟜を討つぞ！
We'll defeat Chengjiao!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
Ancient China.
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望は解放されていた
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
human desire was unleashed.
戦乱の嵐が
500年にわたって吹き荒れ
And a storm of violent wars erupted for 500 years...
100を超えた国々は
７つに淘汰(とうた)された
until over one hundred states were reduced to merely seven.
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the State of Qin in the far West.
そして今 西の果ての国 秦(しん)から―
大いなる歴史が
生まれようとしている
これは
戦乱の時代を生き抜いた―
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
rtrs
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuitous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Qpax
Now's the only time.
～♪
The Roar of Lankai
（廷臣Ａ）うん？
（廷臣Ｂ）何やら外が騒がしい様子
It seems there's some commotion outside.
もしや山の民とモメているのでは…
Could there be a dispute with the Mountain People?
（竭氏(けつし)）ハァハァ…
（竭氏）ハァ…
（成蟜）その慌てよう 珍しいな
どうした？ 丞相(じょうしょう)
It's rare to see you in such a panic.
What's wrong, Chancellor?
The reason the Mountain People came down from the mountains was not to restore an alliance.
（竭氏）こたびの山の民の下山は
盟復活のためにあらず
The 50 people that entered forced their way through the Zhugui Gate...
入城した50人は
朱亀(しゅき)の門を武力で突破し
現在 公龍(こうりゅう)の広間にて
肆氏(しし)の兵300と交戦中
and they are now in combat with 300 of Shi Shi's soldiers in Gongong Plaza.
（廷臣Ｄ）なに？
（廷臣Ｅ）それは…
What?!
Th-That's...!
（竭氏）更に その山の民の中に
Furthermore, seen among those Mountain People was King Ying Zheng.
大王 嬴政(えいせい)の姿あり
だ… 大王ですと？
Th-The king?!
どういうことですか？ 一体
What could this mean?!
（廷臣Ｃ）山の民の中に大王とは…
（廷臣Ｄ）そんなことが…
The king is among the Mountain People?!
How could that...
まさか 山の民を味方につけ
大王自ら 玉座を取り戻しに？
Could he have allied himself with the Mountain People in order to take the throne back for himself?!
うろたえるな
ヤツらが ここまで来ることはない
Do not be flurried! They will never reach this room!
アーハハハッ！
Is that so?
そうか…
そうか やはり生きていたか
So he is alive?
Ying Zheng...
嬴政 フフフッ…
孤立したあげく下等な山猿をお供に
王宮奪還だと？
After being left all on his own, he's made friends with those mountain monkeys to take back the palace?
いかにも下品な貴様らしいやり方だ
An unrefined method truly befitting of you.
だが そんな脆弱(ぜいじゃく)な軍勢で―
But you truly thought you could retake the throne from me with such a frail army?
この俺から 玉座を
取り戻せると思ったのか？ バカめ
You fool!
死をもって思い知るがいい
With your death, may you come to realize...
貴様には
王たる資格がなかったことを
that you did not have the qualifications to be king!
I... am the king!
王は… 俺だ！
（政）全軍 聞けい！
Attention, all forces!
（兵士Ａ）オッ…
（兵士Ｂ）大王！
My king!
Everyone! Do not lose your fighting spirit!
（政）皆の者 戦意を絶つな！
勝利は目前だぞ！
Victory is before our very eyes!
（兵士Ｃ）ハッ…
（兵士Ｄ）勝利が目前？
Victory is... before our eyes?
これは 俺と成蟜の戦い
そして 成蟜の庇護者(ひごしゃ)となり―
This is a battle between Chengjiao and me!
As well as between Chengjiao's protector,
the one planning to take control over the entire State of Qin, Jie Shi!
秦国を牛耳ろうと
たくらむ竭氏との戦いだ
Besides those two, there is no one towing this wicked insurrection!
その２人のほかに この腹黒い
反乱を牽引(けんいん)する人物は いない
２人を失えば 敵は必ず崩壊する！
Without those two, the enemy is sure to crumble!
その２人がいる本殿は もはや丸裸
And the inner palace, where they're hiding, is already completely exposed!
今にも別動隊が襲いかかり
首領２人を討つであろう
Even now, our separate squadron is attacking it and are sure to defeat the two leaders!
俺たちは ただ耐えしのげばいい！
All we must do is to endure until then!
Endure! Even if your swords are broken,
耐えしのげ
剣が折れても 腕をなくしても
even if you lose your arms,
even if you lose every drop of blood, endure!
血を流し尽くしても耐えしのげ
耐えしのげば 俺たちの勝ちだ！
If you endure, it will be our victory!
（貂）ねえ まだなの？ 壁
（壁）もう少しだ　半分は来ている
Hey, is it much further, Bi?
Just a little...
We've come to the half-way point.
We're still only half way?
（貂）まだ半分かよ
なあ 隊長
あの人 休ませたほうがいいよ
Hey, Captain...
Maybe we should let that guy rest.
もうムリだ　死んじゃうよ
He's pushing himself too far, he's gonna die.
（バジオウ）本人が 進もうと
しているのだ　止めることはない
He's choosing on his own to keep moving.
We will not stop him.
And if he dies because of it, then that is fine.
もし そのせいで死んだとしても
それは それでいい
えっ… 何言ってんだ！
What're you saying?!
隊長 なんで そんなこと言うんだよ
Captain! How could you say something like that?!
Diao, Bajiou isn't wrong in what he's saying.
（壁）貂 バジオウが
言っていることは 間違っていない
Bi...
壁…
We're risking everything.
全てが懸かっている
（貂）えっ？
（壁）広間で戦う大王たちの命も
城外で待つ3,000の仲間の命も
The lives of the king and the others fighting in the plaza, as well as the lives of our 3,000 allies outside the castle.
この戦の勝利も
全てが 我々 別動隊に懸かっている
Victory in this battle rides completely on us, the separate squadron.
彼も それが分かっているから
進もうとしている
He continues to move forward knowing that as well.
Until all of his strength is exhausted.
力尽きる そのときまで
It's just a little more. Let's go.
もう少しだ　行こうぜ
（貂）信…
Xin...
よせ 少年 遅れるぞ
Stop, boy. You'll fall behind.
Shut up.
うるせえよ
（信）漂ってヤツがいてよ
This guy, Piao,
俺と同じ孤児なんだ
he was an orphan just like me.
He was like a brother to me growing up...
そいつと 兄弟みてえに育てられた
育てられたっつっても
２人とも下僕だけどな
Though we both grew up as servants.
They say he looks lot like Zheng, but...
そいつが政に似てるっつうんだが
あ～… 今 考えりゃ そうでもねえ
Well, thinking about it now, I don't think so.
Piao was light-hearted through and through and he always smiled...
漂は 根っから明るくて
いっつも笑ってた
政は根暗だぜ ハハハハッ！
But Zheng's just plain gloomy!
It looks like there've been a lot of sacrifices in this rebellion, and Piao was one of them.
今度の反乱で
大勢 犠牲が出たみてえだけど
漂も そのひとりだ
Now that I think of it, the place we're going now is where I can really avenge him.
そう考えると 今から行く所に
本当の敵(かたき)がいるってことだな
Do you have any siblings?
あんた 兄弟とかいるのか？
Well, I guess you can't really talk right now.
…つっても 今しゃべれねえよな
見ろよ　いよいよだぜ
みんな あそこから始まったんだ
Look, we're finally almost there.
All of this began over there.
Xin...
信…
うん？ 遅れてっか？
よし！ ちょっと飛ばすか
Oh, were we falling behind?
Okay, we'll just do a little sprint!
Xin...
信…
その人…
（信）えっ？
That man is...
もう… 死んでるよ
already... dead.
（役人たち）ヒイッ…
どけ！
（役人たち）アアッ！
Out of the way!
ヒイ～ッ…
Who were those guys?
何だ？ あいつら　兵士じゃない
They weren't soldiers!
本殿仕えの者たちだ
ここから先は皆 丸腰だ
They're people that serve the inner palace.
Everyone past here is unarmed.
（貂）本殿が近いってこと？
（壁）近いなんてもんじゃない
So the inner palace is close?
It's not just close,
すぐ目の前だ
it'll be before our eyes at any second!
It's over, you wretches!
終わりだ 悪党ども！
き… き… 来た！
（廷臣たち）ヒイッ…
How in the world did you bastards get here?!
貴様ら 一体 どうやって ここへ…
左慈め しくじりおったのか
Did that bastard, Zuoci, fail?!
お前が成蟜か？
So you're Chengjiao?
That's a surprise.
意外だぜ　泣きわめいて
逃げ回ると思ってたんだが
I expected you to be running around, crying like a baby,
余裕あるじゃねえか
覚悟できてんだろうな？ てめえ
but you're pretty damn composed.
I guess you're prepared for what's coming to you.
Death.
（成蟜）死罪だ
The punishment for vulgar people like you setting foot in this noble royal palace is... death.
貴様らのような下等な輩(やから)が
高貴な王宮に踏み入った罪で 死罪
ンンッ…
（成蟜）貴様らゴミ虫が―
The punishment for pieces of shit like you breathing the same air as me is... death.
俺と同じ場所で
息をしている罪で 死罪
ヘヘヘヘッ… そんなもんだろうな
Ah, I get it.
That reaction you gave is probably the most typical one for royalty.
今のお前の反応が
いちばん王族らしいと思うぜ
ずっと あいつと一緒だったから
忘れてた
Having been with that guy this whole time, I forgot.
王に向かって“お前”とは何事だ？
貴様 おかしいのか？
How dare you address a king as "you".
Are you out of your mind?
Hey, hey! I think the crazy one here is you!
おいおい おかしいのは お前だろう
The king of the State of Qin is Zheng!
秦国の大王は政だ
お前は ただの反逆者だ！
You're nothing but a traitor!
Don't think you bastards will simply get off with death.
貴様 ただで死ねると思うなよ
生きながら手足を引きちぎってやる
I'll see that your limbs are torn off while you're still alive.
やってみろよ
Just try.
Lankai!
ランカイ！
何だ てめえは！ ヤーッ！
What the hell are you?!
It won't cut!
斬れねえ…
ウワーッ！
Xin!
信！
な… 何だ？ こいつは
Wh-What is this guy...?
何なんだ？ こいつは
Seriously, what is this thing?!
It's Lankai.
ランカイだよ
Are you there, Teng?
（王騎(おうき)）騰(とう)は いますか？
Yes, right here, sir.
（騰）はっ！ ここに
Are you going to the corridor?
（王騎）
あなた 回廊に行ったのでは？
はっ… 今から向かおうかと
（王騎）もう結構です
I was about to go now.
There's no longer any need.
あなたには 別に
行っていただきたい場所があります
There's somewhere else I'd like you to go.
Understood, sir!
はっ！ 承りました
今すぐですよ
（騰）はっ！
Right away.
Sir!
It sure is taking a long time...
（隊長Ａ）遅いな
中は 一体 どうなっているのだ？
What on earth is going on inside?
I know we were told to wait on standby, but wouldn't it be better if we got moving?
（隊長Ｂ）待機とのことだったが
動いたほうがいいのではないか？
（隊長Ｃ）そうだ　８万の軍が
来る前に 門を破り 再び閉じれば…
That's true.
If we broke through the gate, before the army of 80,000 arrives, and then close it after us...
（隊長Ａ）そのとおりだ
Exactly.
（長老Ａ）
勝手なマネはするな アホが
Do not start acting on your own, fools!
（長老Ｂ）
命令が待機なら 待機じゃ アホが
If your orders are to standby, then standby, fools!
隊長や
タジフたちの力も通じないなんて…
Even Captain and Tajif's strength isn't doing anything...
あんな化け物 どうやって…
How do you kill a monster like that...?!
None of you interfere.
（バジオウ）誰も手を出すな
Bajiou... What are you planning to do?
バジオウ どうするつもりだ？
しばし 昔に戻るぞ
For a brief time, I'll return to whom I used to be.
ハァ～ッ…
（隊長Ａ）山の民の長老の言葉なら
こちらも従いたいところだが…
I'd like to obey the words of Mountain People elders, but...
（長老Ａ）我らは王を信じておる
We believe in the king.
A-As do we, but...
そ… それは我々も同じだ
しかし…
中にいるのは 選び抜かれた者たち
The ones in there are the chosen elite.
こちらから出した40人は
各部族の手だれ
The 40 people sent past here are the most skilled from each tribe.
そして それを率いておるのは
山の王 楊端和(ようたんわ)さま
And the one leading them is the Mountain King, her majesty Yang Duan He.
Bajiou is there as well.
それに バジオウもいる
What agility!
なんという身のこなしだ…
化け物が嫌がってる　形勢逆転だ
He's angering the monster.
The situation's been reversed.
You're so awesome, Captain!
すげえ 隊長
（貂）すげえけど なんか怖(こえ)え…
You're incredible, but... kind of scary.
あれは人間じゃない… 野獣だ
That's not a human... it's a wild beast!
Bajiou?
バジオウ…
信が“隊長”と呼んでる男か
The man Xin calls "Captain"?
バジオウは 哀れなガキじゃった
Bajiou was a miserable brat.
我らが 山界統一のため
遠征に出たばかりのころ
In the days, when we had just started to campaign for uniting the Mountain World,
北の深山に 分け入ったとき
見張りの３人が 姿を消した
when we were pushing our way through the deep northern mountains, three guards disappeared.
近くを捜してみると
３人の死体があった
When we searched for them nearby, all we found were three corpses.
どれも 獣に襲われたような
むごい ありさまでのぅ
Each of them were in a gruesome state like they had been attacked by a beast.
There was a yet-undiscovered brutal enemy in that land.
“この地には
まだ見ぬ凶暴な敵がいる”
20人の隊を作り 周りを探らせた
We formed a 20-man squadron and searched the area.
だが
どれだけたっても 誰ひとり戻らぬ
But no matter how many we sent, not one returned.
Filled with a sense of foreboding, we mobilized our main force...
イヤな予感がした我らは
本隊を動かし
消えた20名の隊を捜すことにした
to look for the 20 missing soldiers.
すると 捜索を始めて程なく
我らは獣を見つけた
We had barely even begun the search when we found the beast.
そして ヤツの周りには
20人の無残な亡骸(なきがら)があった
And around him was the awful sight of 20 corpses.
（長老Ａ）バジオウの一族は
数年前の戦で滅び―
Bajiou's tribe was wiped out several years earlier and he was the only survivor.
ヤツのみが生き残った
山の中 何年も１人で生きるうちに
ヤツは人ではなくなったのじゃ
After living several years alone in the mountains he lost his humanity.
ヤツを取り押さえるのは
大変じゃったぞ ハハハハッ…
He was quite difficult to restrain.
（バジオウ）
アッ… ガアッ… アア…
If you remain as a beast, you will be slain here and now.
（楊端和）貴様が獣のままならば
今ここで とどめを刺す
But if you return to being a human and swear loyalty to me,
しかし 人に戻り
私に忠誠を誓うならば―
家族として迎え入れる
I will welcome you in as family.
At that time, Bajiou did not know any human language.
（長老Ａ）あのとき バジオウは
人の言葉は分かってはおらんかった
But even so, he cried and let out a loud scream.
だが それでも大声で泣いた
そうして 楊端和さまは
バジオウを一族に迎え入れた
And so, Lord Yang Duan He took him in as part of her tribe.
Bajiou gradually regained his humanity,
バジオウは
しだいに人間性を取り戻し
言葉も覚え 有能な戦士となった
learned language, and became a skilled warrior.
じゃがな…
But...
even now, it lurks deep inside him.
あやつの中には 今でも潜んでおる
あのころの獣がな
The beast from those days.
もしも その獣が解放されたときは
If that beast were to be released,
手に負えぬぞ ハハハハッ…
he'd become uncontrollable.
すげえ…
Incredible...
速い…
He's fast!
（刺す音）
グアーッ！
信じられん
Unbelievable!
あの化け物を完全に翻弄している
That monster is at his utter mercy!
This is the true form of Bajiou?!
これが バジオウの本当の姿か…
いいぞ 隊長！
That's it, Captain!
The monster is... retreating.
化け物が… 下がってる
ランカイが押されておるぞ…
Lankai is... being pushed back!
まさか… あの怪物が負ける？
It can't be...
That monster is losing?!
勝った… すげえや 隊長
あの怪物をやっつけた！
He won.
Awesome, Captain!
You really beat that monster!
What gargantuan strength...!
なんという強さだ…
これで あとは成蟜を討つのみ
Now all that's left is Chengjiao!
（成蟜）ランカイ！
（ランカイ）ウッ…
Lankai!
誰が休めと言った！
Who told you to rest?!
何のために 貴様のような化け物を
飼ってきたと思っている？
Why the hell do you think I've been keeping a monster like you as a pet?!
I'm sure I've told you.
教えたはずだ　貴様の存在価値は
人を殺すことだけだと
The only purpose to your existence is to kill people.
Now hurry up and crush them.
さっさと たたきつぶせ
さもなくば―
Because if you don't...
you'll be punished.
お仕置きだぞ
Do it. Finish them!
やれ　そいつらに とどめを
隊長ーっ！
Captain!
kowaresou na kokoro tsumugu youni
壊れそうな心 紡ぐように
To weave together my breaking heart
yume no kakera mitsume (No more cry)
夢のカケラ見つめ (No more cry）
I gaze at the fragments of a dream (No more crying)
me no mae ni wa tsuki ga utsushidasu
目の前には月が映し出す
The moon I see before my eyes
kono mune no yakusoku
この胸の約束
reflects this promise in my heart
～♪
namida ga nokoshita kioku sae mo
涙が残した記憶さえも
I won't turn away from my tearful memories
（信）“点”と“線” 悪くねえ
waraiatta kako sae furimukanai
笑いあった過去さえ振り向かない
nor the past where we laughed together
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）打つ手は尽きた
立ち上がれる者は もはや なし
Voice of soul
次回 “剣の力”
Voice of you
kanashimi nara kitto tsuyosa ni kawaru hazu
悲しみならきっと 強さに変わるはず
Sadness is sure to turn into strength
I won't cry
I won't fear
I won't stop
takaku tobeba kitto sora no mukou ni todoku
高く翔べばきっと空の向こうに届く
If I jump high enough, I'm sure I'll reach beyond the sky
Voice of mine
Yeah
Voice of soul
Preview
Lines and...
a point.
Not bad!
With all options exhausted,
there is no one left who can stand.
The Power of the Sword
Next time,
End
The Power of the Sword